DIPL.-ING. DENNIS MÜNCHOW

Digitalization Engineer with 5+ years experience in the automotive & chemistry industry, leading cross-functional projects in engineering and production with a focus on digitalization and process optimization.

Born 21. July 1993 in Wolfen, Germany



SUMMARY

Experienced Digitalization Engineer leading international projects for multiple of the most successful global players in the German automotive & chemistry industry. Gained detailed insights into production and IT business areas while interfacing with engineering, planning, and logistics across the entire value chain. Confident stakeholder communicator and task coordinator during critical project situations to deliver exceptional results at executive level. Google certified Data Analyst with a strong passion for process optimization and automation, data visualization & peak efficiency.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- · Program & multi project management
- Strategy development & implementation
- · Process optimization & automation
- · Google certified Data Analyst
- · Business Intelligence Consulting
- · Open-minded communicator

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer | Digitalization Engineer

01.2023 - present

Specialisation: Digital Transformation

- · Supporting companies on their journey of the digital transformation
- · Focus on strategic project management, robotic process automation & dashboard creation

BASF Schwarzheide GmbH | Digitalization Engineer

12.2021 - present

Department: Digitalization | Strategy

- · Strategy lead for autonomous robots for industrial inspection
- · Project lead and scripter for robotic process automation

MHP - A Porsche Company | Management Consultant

07.2019 - 11.2021

Department: Operations Excellence | Performance & Strategy

- · Project management of various IT harmonization projects
- · Programming of VBA-based analysis tools

Porsche Leipzig GmbH | Master Thesis Student

05.2018 - 03.2019

Department: Production Planning | Body Shop

- · Project management for process development with a Canadian start-up
- · Master Thesis: Analysis of process variables in air-coupled ultrasonic testing of resistance spot welds (Final Grade: 1,4)

Composite Cluster Singapore | Internship

10.2017 - 03.2018

Department: Prototype Development | Lightweight Engineering

· Planning, conception and production of the first prototype series

Institute of Lightweight Engineering and Polymer Technology | Working Student

05.2016- 09.2017

Department: Process Development | Thermoplastic Processes

· Analysis and evaluation of critical process parameters

Daimler AG | Bachelor Thesis Student

09.2015 - 02.2016

Department: Production Planning | Polymer-Metal-Hybrids

· Bachelor Thesis: Process investigation for the pretreatment of carbon fiber rovings for a melt impregnation process (Final Grade: 1,7)

Kochstraße 32, 04275 Leipzig | +49 (0) 176 8223 2007 | dennis.muenchow@outlook.com

EDUCATION

Technische Universität Dresden

10.2012 - 03.2019

- · Subject: Mechanical Engineering
- · Specialisation: Lightweight Engineering and Polymer Technology

PROJECT EXPERTISE

Strategic Development of the Software Lifecycle Management | Automotive OEM

11.2020 - 11.2021

- · Historically grown software portfolios generate high cybersecurity risks
- · Development of End2End-Processes for the Software Lifecycle
- · Cost reduction of 282.000€ in the first eight weeks

Digital Transformation Logistics | Premium Automotive OEM

04.2020 - 09.2020

- · Increasing supply risks arising from globalized supply networks
- · Programming of an VBA-based Controlling-Tool for the support of data driven decisions
- · Synchronization between different brand stakeholders

Harmonizing the IT System Landscape | Automotive OEM

07.2019 - 03.2020

- · Heterogeneous processes and diverse IT landscapes
- · Programming of an VBA-based analysis tool for the status quo of the IT landscape
- · Over six hundred users of multiple cross-functional teams

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Languages German (native), English (fluent)

Technologies Jira, MS Office, MS VBA, MS Visio, MS Power BI, MS SQL Server, Python, UiPath Studio

Certificates Google Data Analytics, Python Core, RPA Developer Advanced, Scrum Master, SQL Course

Interests Data as an Asset, Economics, Guitars, Robotics

Leipzig | 2023

D. Muenchow

Dennis Münchow